Guide to the Charles Alexander Long Papers, 1889-1979 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles Alexander Long papers 1889-1979 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Long, Charles Alexander
11 linear feet Extent: 8,273 Items
Methodist clergyman, missionary, and educator, of Ardmore, Oklahoma Chiefly personal and family correspondence concerning the work of Long and his wife, Lucy Maie (York) Long, as Methodist missionaries in Brazil (1911-1952), where he was also an official and teacher at Granbery Institute, Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil. Correspondents include Bishop César Dacorso Filho, John Monroe Moore, and Hugh Clarence Tucker in Brazil, and evangelist Davidson Victor York in the U.S. Other materials include writings, sermon notes, photographs, manuscript volumes, and printed materials, almost all relating to Long's activities in Brazil. Additions in the 1980s were processed separately from the main collection, and some unprocessed materials remain..
RL.00850
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charles Alexander Long Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 1969-1986.
Collection Overview
The Charles Alexander Long Papers span the years 1879-1989, with most of the materials dating from the twentieth century. The largest group of materials consists of personal and family correspondence concerning the work of Long and his wife, Lucy Maie (York) Long, as Methodist missionaries in Brazil (1911-1952), where he was also an official and teacher at Granbery Institute, Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil. Correspondents include Bishop César Dacorso Filho, John Monroe Moore, and Hugh Clarence Tucker in Brazil, and evangelist Davidson Victor York in the U.S. Other materials include writings, sermon notes, photographs, manuscript volumes, and printed materials such as clippings, almost all relating to Long's activities in Brazil. Additions in the 1980s were processed separately from the main collection, and some unprocessed materials remain.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Filho, César Dacorso; Moore, John M. (John Monroe), 1867-1948; Tucker, Hugh C. (Hugh Clarence), 1857-1956; York, Davidson Victor; Granbery Institute (Juiz de Fora, Brazil).; Methodist Church -- Brazil; Methodist Church -- Missions; Missions -- Brazil; Schools -- Brazil -- Juiz de Fora; Women missionaries -- Brazil
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1892-1970 and undated, (28 boxes)
  - 1892-1910 (Box 2)
  - 1911 (Box 3)
  - 1912-1915 (Box 4)
  - 1916-1920 Mar. (Box 5)
  - 1920 Apr.-1921 (Box 6)
  - 1922-1925 (Box 7)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 8)
  - 1928 (Box 9)
  - 1929-1930 May (Box 10)
  - 1930 June-1932 May (Box 11)
  - 1932 June-1933 (Box 12)
  - 1934-1935 July (Box 13)
  - 1935 Aug.-1936 (Box 14)
  - 1937-1940 (Box 15)
  - 1941-1945 Sept. (Box 16)
  - 1945 Oct.-1946 Oct. (Box 17)
  - 1946 Nov.-1947 June (Box 18)
  - 1947 July-1949 (Box 19)
  - 1950-1952 May (Box 20)
  - 1952 June-1954 (Box 21)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 22)
  - 1958-1960 May (Box 23)
  - 1960 June-1963 (Box 24)
  - 1964-1965 Sept. (Box 25)
  - 1965 Oct.-1967 July (Box 26)
  - 1967 Aug.-1968 (Box 27)
  - 1969-1970 and undated (Box 29)
- Financial and Legal Papers Series, (1 box)
  - Financial and legal papers (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous Papers Series, (3 boxes)
  - Papers, including genealogical material (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous: genealogy, biography (Box 32)
- Writings Series, (3 boxes)
  - Writings (Box 30)
  - Writings, sermon notes (Box 31)
  - Writings (Box 32)
- Printed Material Series, (12 boxes)
  - Printed Material (Box 33)
  - Clippings (Box 34)
  - Printed Material (Box 34-35)
  - Clippings (Box 36-37)
  - Printed Material (Box 38-42)
  - Printed Material, magazines (Box 46-47)
- Pictures Series, (4 boxes)
  - Pictures (Box 43-45, 48)
- Manuscript Volumes and Additional Papers Series, 1906-1940s, (2 boxes)
  - Volumes and additional papers (Box 49-50)
    Miscellaneous papers (box 49) and account and memoranda books (box 50), some with Methodist Church tithing information, dating to Long's time in Brazil, 1920s-1940s; also, a 1906 yearbook from the Centenary Female College in Cleveland, Tennessee (Box 50).
- Additions (1980), 1889-1979 and undated, (5 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1889-1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Writings, 1917-1979 and undated (Box 4)
  - Printed Material, 1942-1977 and undated (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed items (Box 6-10)
- Oversize Materials
  - Blueprints for A Study of Deep Wells in the Southern Part of the Great Plains Region, Bachelors Thesis, University of Oklahoma, 1905 (Opaperfolder OF1)
  - Diplomas
  - Poster, color, 1932